# FABIO A. NAVARRETE HIGUERA E-mail: fabioanh@gmail.com

Tel: +32 493169603

Location: Berlin, Germany

### Brief Profile:



Software engineer born 1988 in Colombia. I enjoy solving scientific and technical problems and I'm eager to learn new things. Creativity is one of my main drivers, so I enjoy using the different skills I possess. I like to keep my interests diversified and I thrive developing software. I've been working professionally for around 9 years. Being part of multiple software teams in 5 different countries, I learnt a wide range of technologies. Java has kept me busy most of the time, but I also used Python and Kotlin in academic and personal projects. My strongest skills are related to the design and development of RESTful APIs. I'm eager to join a challenging environment where I could keep learning and sharing knowledge. At the moment I bluow like to contribute environmental cause.

## Academic Background:



Systems Engineer (Bachelor of Science) -Universidad Nacional de Colombia - 2010

# Information Technology Tools:



Java 👙	Python 🤚	Linux
Spring ፘ	Postgres 📭	Flutter
Hibernate な	Oracle	TensorFlow
RESTful {}	Jira💠	JUnit
Git 🚸	JMeter /jMeter	Mockito
AWS aws	Jenkins 🧌	Kotlin
Solr 🧶	Google Cloud	2
MongoDB 🌗	Kubernetes 🚱	
Spring Boot		

#### Miscellaneous:

Interested in the study of complex Artificial Intelligence. systems and Curious about social simulations and anthropology. Amateur drums player. like to teach, and constantly improve my skills. Fond of hiking and nature contemplation.

### Job History:



### ubitricity(Jun 2021 - Present)

Development of platform for charging point provider. Rest APT spring-boot microservices on Google Cloud. Scrum team.



#### **IPlytics** (Sept 2020 - May 2021)

Intelectual property development. Web App using Spring Boot. Cloud migration, Azure Kubernetes.



Proximus (Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 Belgium)

Web-shop development mostly involved with the Rest API. Scrum teams, project with around 30 people total.



Adneom (Jun 2016 - Dec 2017 Belgium)

Consultancy work for ENGIE: support during migration of web application backend from Java to Python. BPost: JEE app.



#### **Advaita** (Nov 2013 - Sep 2015 USA)

Development of a RESTful API using Spring, in order to commercialise a stalled product for a bioinformatics start-



**Globant** (Jun 2012 - Oct 2013 Colombia)

JEE development. Worked on several applications for external clients. Additional tests automation tasks.



### Spoken Languages:

English - C1 French - B2 German - A2 Italian - A2 Spanish - Native